# Jason Bergener

github.com/jasonbergener

(706)-577-7829 | jasonbergener@outlook.com | linkedin.com/in/jasonbergener

# **SUMMARY**

A dedicated and experienced professional with a passion for information technology who carefully analyzes requirements, develops solutions, and leverages appropriate resources to accomplish goals. Demonstrates initiative and possesses all characteristics to be a part of a talented team where learning from peers and growing as a team is a fundamental theme.

## **OUALIFICATIONS**

<ul> <li>Problem Solving</li> </ul>	• C#	• Java
• SQL	• .NET	• Azure
• HTML	• CSS	• Scrum

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Student, Microsoft Software and Systems Academy (MSSA)

**Expected Graduation 2017** 

## **Cloud Application Development, Fort Benning, GA**

MSSA is an 18-week accelerated full-time, hands-on IT training program developed by Microsoft. The program leverages college accredited courses and the goal of preparing transitioning service members for careers in technology.

- Designed, composed, and built applications using C#.
- Designed, composed, and built applications using the ASP.NET MVC framework.
- Designed, composed, built, and managed SQL databases using Microsoft SQL Server.
- Experience with Azure cloud platform.
- Performed unit and integration testing to validate solutions with C# and ASP.NET projects.

U.S. Army 1998 - Present

## **Operations Supervisor III**

Fort Benning, GA (2013 – Present)

- Implemented custom JavaScript with Adobe Acrobat to automate employee time sheets reducing the overall processing time by 4 hours each week.
- Analyzed over 1200 corporate level directives and enhanced processes resulting in timely dissemination of information with over 90% of tasks completed ahead of time.
- Recommended and implemented changes to procedures for disseminating instructions to subordinates, resulting in a 70% decrease to the processing time.
- Received, analyzed, and developed recommended plans of action for corporate level executives to drive daily performance.
- Distributed directives to subsidiary organizations and conducted conflict resolution where necessary.
- Planned and oversaw the completion of 5 annual training events impacting over 6000 personnel.

## **Operations Supervisor II**

Schofield Barracks, HI (2010 – 2013)

- Selected over 3 senior supervisors and 4 peers to serve as a Senior Operations Manager in extreme and arduous conditions that depended on results (awarded a Bronze Star).
- Recognized by the Sergeant Major of the Army for outstanding performance in hazardous conditions.
- Coordinated the setup, security, internal organization, work distribution, and displacement of a mobile operations center and proprietary computer systems.
- Maintained the accountability and readiness of all assigned materials and IT equipment valued at more than \$4,000,000.
- Provided technical guidance and support to employees on all administrative matters.
- Oversaw the organization's training program.

# **Operations Supervisor**

Fort Jackson, SC (2009 – 2010)

- Recognized by the Senior Manager for providing an outstanding training environment that facilitated realistic training for over 16,000 employees.
- Demonstrated expert knowledge during two critical safety and environmental compliance audits.
- Improved and maintained a simulated training environment.
- Researched information regarding current trends in the industry and implemented updated procedures.

# **Logistics Manager**

Fort Jackson, SC (2008 – 2009)

2013

- Coordinated logistical support for a training organization that trained over 30,000 employees annually.
- Demonstrated adaptability when recognized for excellence while working outside of my specialty field.
- Prepared presentations and briefed logistical and facility statuses enabling senior leadership to make informed and timely decisions.

#### **Supervisor**

Joint Base Lewis-McChord, WA (2006 – 2008)

- Exercised critical thinking and problem-solving skills in an 8-person team environment during an organizational team building competition achieving 1st place out of 12 teams.
- Managed 6 employees and 2 supervisors.
- Assisted senior management with developing and implementing individual and collective training.

Earlier roles in the U.S. Army include communication specialist, driver, and team member.

#### **EDUCATION**

- **Trident University International** Expected Graduation February 2018 B.S. in Computer Science: Cyber Security (Current GPA is 4.0)
- Hawaii Pacific University
  A.S. in Computer Science (with Honors).

#### **CERTIFICATIONS AND TRAINING**

- MTA: 98-361, Software Development Fundamentals 2017
- Scrum Basics 2017